{
    "id": "7f051e72994e4c92bda3709874279bdd",
    "title": "Mixed Conditionals Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "If I were you, I …………………………… this.",
            "description": "When the verb in the if-clause is in the simple past tense, we use would + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "won't do",
                "wouldn't do",
                "wouldn't have done"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "5ce8961db2ec4437b673558bac917946"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ………………………. red and green, you will get yellow.",
            "description": "In the first conditional we use a simple present tense in the if clause and will + infinitive in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "mix",
                "will mix",
                "would mix"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "eae78a2a529f400785ec449a963d2c2b"
        },
        {
            "question": "Unless you ……………………….. smoking, you will get cancer.",
            "description": "Unless means if not.",
            "answers": [
                "quit",
                "don't quit",
                "won't quit"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "e3e8801cd711497bba0cca83894f0c81"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you …………………………. your ways, you will land in serious trouble.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "not mend",
                "mend",
                "don't mend"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "ed984860eb454f7eb3dc25c4626d6dc5"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you had called me, I ………………………. come immediately.",
            "description": "\r\nIn the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "would",
                "would have"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "1045481e96aa4e4883aad66ef18ba59c"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you start now, you ………………………. there on time.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + infinitive in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will reach",
                "would reach",
                "would have reached"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "9b154657c1a3477cbec1754dbed78d6e"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I learned electronics at college, I ………………………… an engineer.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would / could + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "can become",
                "could become",
                "could have become"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "36c6edb850d84c5b8335381767ab74a3"
        },
        {
            "question": "Unless you stop drinking, you ……………………….. liver trouble.",
            "description": "Unless means if not. This sentence can also be written as: If you do not stop drinking, you will develop liver trouble.\r\n",
            "answers": [
                "will develop",
                "will not develop"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "e80411ddad5045569d80e2117a7ffe69"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you see him, ………………………… him to visit me?",
            "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + infinitive in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will you ask",
                "would you ask",
                "would you have asked"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "c1b9892c84c341c0a6f472c14f10c9fe"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ………………………. into James, tell him that I am getting married.",
            "description": "We can use should in the first conditional to suggest that something is very unlikely.",
            "answers": [
                "run",
                "should run",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "ed16eee6b25c4408aa5b94e496a01e96"
        },
        {
            "question": "If he ……………………… late, we will have to leave without him.",
            "description": "Should is possible in the first conditional.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "should be",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "0b52319f100c476cb3a42da457981f09"
        },
        {
            "question": "What would you do if you …………………….. to lose your job?",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would / could + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "are",
                "were",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "6527177a9b7d40d18ade7e526f9adf18"
        }
    ]
}